In this American English pronunciation video, we're going to learn how to pronounce the CH and JJ consonants.
在这段美式英语发音视频中，我们将学习如何发音CH和JJ辅音。
The CH and JJ consonants are paired together because they take the same mouth position.
CH和JJ辅音被放在一起，因为它们的口腔位置相同。
CH is unvoiced, meaning only air passes through the mouth, and JJ is voiced, meaning you make a sound with the vocal cords.
CH是无声的，意味着只有空气通过口腔，而JJ是有声的，意味着你用声带发出声音。
JJ.
JJ。
These consonants have a stop consonant component, but unlike stop consonants, they're always released.
这些辅音有一个爆破音的成分，但与爆破音不同的是，它们总是被释放出来。
They each contain two sounds.
它们每个包含两个声音。
For the CH, we're combining the T, tt, and the SH, sh, to make ch.
对于CH，我们将T, tt和SH, sh结合起来发出ch。
For the J sound, we're combining dd and zj to make jj.
对于J音，我们将dd和zj结合起来发出jj。
The teeth come together and the lips flare, just like in the SH and ZJ sounds.
牙齿合拢，嘴唇张开，就像在SH和ZJ音中一样。
But the tongue position is like the Tt and dd sounds.
但舌头的位置像Tt和dd音。
The tongue lifts so the front, flat part of the tongue touches the roof of the mouth.
舌头抬起，使舌头的前平面部分接触上颚。
We stop the air in our throat, and then we release everything.
我们在喉咙中阻止空气，然后释放一切。
Ch.
Ch。
Jj.
Jj。
We release the air at the vocal cords, release the tongue down from the roof of the mouth, release the teeth so they part a little, and release the lips by relaxing them.
我们在声带处释放空气，从上颚释放舌头，释放牙齿使它们稍微分开，并通过放松嘴唇来释放嘴唇。
Ch.
Ch。
Jj.
Jj。
Let's look at these sounds up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作观察这些声音。
The lips flare and the teeth come together.
嘴唇张开，牙齿合拢。
Then the release.
然后释放。
The word JAR.
单词JAR。
The lips flare and the teeth come together.
嘴唇张开，牙齿合拢。
Then release into the AH as in FATHER vowel.
然后释放成AH音，如FATHER中的元音。
The word CHART.
单词CHART。
The lips flare and the teeth come together.
嘴唇张开，牙齿合拢。
Then release into the AH as in FATHER vowel.
然后释放成AH音，如FATHER中的元音。
The word BATCH.
单词BATCH。
The lips flare and the teeth come together.
嘴唇张开，牙齿合拢。
Then release.
然后释放。
The CH and J consonants.
CH和J辅音。
JAR.
JAR。
CHART.
CHART。
Batch.
Batch。
Example words.
示例单词。
Practice with me.
跟我练习。
Chase.
Chase。
Ch.
Ch。
Chase.
Chase。
Attach.
Attach。
Ch.
Ch。
Attach.
Attach。
Teacher.
Teacher。
Ch.
Ch。
Teacher.
Teacher。
Danger.
Danger。
J.
J。
Danger.
Danger。
Just.
Just。
J.
J。
Just.
Just。
General.
General。
J.
J。
General.
General。